- [Narrator] WebGL is a
low level JavaScript API
that enables creation
and display of 3D content
inside the browser using the GPU.
It's supported by every
modem browser out there,
except for some older versions
of IE and Android browser.
Unfortunately, since
WebGL is a low-level API,
it can be a bit hard and tedious to use.
You need to write
hundreds of lines of codes
to even perform even the simplest tasks.
Three.js on the other hand
is an open-source JavaScript
library that abstracts away
the complexity of WebGL
and allows us to create
real-time 3D content
in a much easier manner.
In this course, we will be learning
about this amazing technology.
Three.js have been around for a while
and have a great support
and community behind it.
Visiting the Three.js website,
you can check out the links
on the main page and see
the amazing body of work
created using this library.
I will just quickly show
you three of my favorites.
Here is a 3D data visualization
that displays the global
oil imports and exports
for various countries.
You can be interacting
with the visualization
and see the data for various countries
and for various years as well.
This a game of visualization
and an exercise
on how far you could be pushing
the 3D graphics on the web.
I really like the photo
realism on this one.
And this another Three.js exercise
that I really like as well.
This is a product page for Renault,
where you can see and
interact with the car in 3D.
You can even animate it with
pressing these buttons here.
It's impressive that this kind of content
can now be created inside the browser
and can run cross
platform without the need
of any plugins or add ons.
In these examples, you
can see clear use cases
of how Three.js can be leveraged
in the context of entertainment,
advertisement, education,
or E-commerce.
With the inevitable rise
of VR and AR, 3D content
is bound to become an even
larger part of our lives.
Three.js makes creating and distribution
of such content really easy,
using one of the most
accessible technology platforms
of all time.
The browser.