- [Instructor] When using
Three.js, you will need to serve
your HTML file through a
server to be able to load in
some of the assets that we
will be using in this course.
If you are looking for a
server that is easy to set up,
you can use Python to start a simple
HTTP server using this comment.
This comment assumes
you are using Python 2.
If you are using Python
3, this is the comment
that you should use, or you
could install third party
solutions as well, I'm using
a tool called live-server
that I installed through MPM.
It supports live reloading of files
whenever there is a change in them.
You can find that tool on this page.
You will have the server running
at the root of the project files.
We can start live-server
by typing live-server
inside the terminal, I will
have the server running
at the root of my project files.
If you want to use Three.js in production,
you can find the minified version
of the library on their GitHub page.
A minified file is smaller
in size and has more
efficient use in production,
why debugging is harder
when using a minified
file is the error messages
that you get can be a bit cryptic.
Therefore, for development
and for our purposes
in this course we will
be using a non-minified
version of the Three.js library.
You can find both the minified
and non-minified versions
of Three.js library on
their GitHub repository.
I have already included Three.js
in project downloadables.
At the time of this recording, Three.js
is at the release number 85.
Here we have a pretty simple HTML file.
We are loading in the Three.js library
for it to be available for our use.
It has been loaded on this line.
We are also pointing to
another JavaScript file
which we will be creating to
write our Three.js codes in,
which is this line.
The HTML has a div
amount with a unique ID.
We will be using this
ID to be able to select
the div amounts from our JavaScript code,
and append our 3D content to it.
You also have some very simple
styling declarations that is here.
Here in our main .js file,
which is right now anti,
I will just type in console.log(THREE)
to ensure that Three.js library
is properly loaded, and
now inside the browser,
inside the console of the inspector,
I can see the Three.js
library being loaded.
We are now ready to start
writing Three.js code.