- [Instructor] When working with Three.js,
and with 3D in general, there are a couple
of required objects we need to have.
One of the first things that
we need is a scene object.
You can think of a scene
object as a container
for any other 3D object that
you are planning to work with.
It represents the 3D world
that we will be building.
We can create the scene
object by doing this.
First, I'm going to remove
the console.log line
that is here, and load create a variable
called scene, and then
initiate Three.js Scene object.
Another thing that we need to have
when working with 3D is the camera.
Think of camera like the
eyes that we will be viewing
this 3D world through.
When working with a 2D visualization,
the concept of a camera
usually doesn't exist.
What you see is what you get, but in 3D,
you need a camera to
define your point of view,
as there are many positions and angles
that you could be looking
at the scene from.
A Three.js camera requires several options
to be provided during the initialization,
such as field of view, aspect ratio,
and near and far clipping planes.
So here, let's initialize the camera,
which is going to be a
Three.js PerspectiveCamera,
and first, we will define a field of view
that defines how much of the
scene that we are seeing,
and then we will define the aspect ratio,
which is going to be the window.innerWidth
divided by window.innerHeight,
and then we will define the
near and far clipping planes.
Of these parameters, the
near and far clipping planes
might look at bit different.
They're mainly there for
optimization purposes.
Anything beyond these
distances won't be visible
in our scene, and won't be
included in the calculations
that you'll be generating with the image.
The camera captures the
scene for display purposes,
but for us to actually see anything,
the 3D data needs to be
converted into a 2D image.
This process is called rendering,
and Three.js comes with
couple of renderers.
We will be using the WebGLRenderer.
You can initialize the
WebGLRenderer like this.
Three.js have other
renderers such as Canvas
or the SVGRenderer.
These renderers can be
useful when you are working
in an environment that
doesn't support WebGL,
but the problem is that,
since they are using CPU
instead of the GPU for their calculations,
the processing of the
image is a lot slower.
Also some of the features of WebGL
such as shadows or
shaders are not available
to these renderers.
This means that the end user experience
using these won't be so great,
so you shouldn't really rely on them
to deliver engaging visual experiences.
We will need to set the
size of the renderer,
which will dictate the
size of the visual output.
It's a good idea to have
the size of the renderer
proportional to the window.innerHeight
and window.innerWidth
so I will first put in the innerWidth,
and then I will provide
the window.innerHeight.
To be able to display the
results of the renderer,
we need to append the
domElement for the renderer
to our HTML content.
We will use the empty div element
that has the ID webgl for this purpose.
So here, we will be using the document,
getElementById method to be able
to select the webgl div element,
and then I will add the
rendering domElement
to this empty div that has the ID webgl,
and having done all this,
now, if you are to call the
render method on the renderer
by providing the scene, and
the camera is the argument,
we should start seeing things.
So if I'm to call the renderer method
on the render, using the scene,
and the camera, things should work,
but first of all, I'm
going to put everything
inside a function called init
to have things a little
bit more tidied up,
and I will call this function instead.
Now, if you are to check out Chrome,
you should start seeing things.
So looking at Chrome, it seems
like we are getting an error,
and the error is on line 12,
saying that render is not defined.
Let's go back to our file
to see what's going wrong.
If I'm to look at this line,
this is render.setSize,
but setSize is a method on the render,
so I have a typo here.
I'm going to just change it to renderer,
and save the file again.
Now if you are to go back to Chrome,
you should see everything is working,
and it seems like we
are now seeing nothing.
The problem is that even
though our setup is working,
since we didn't include
any objects in our scene,
we are just getting a black screen,
which is equivalent to empty space.
We need to populate the scene with objects
to be able to see something.
Let's do that next.