- [Instructor] Let's create
a simple rectangular object
to be able to validate
that everything is working
in our scene.
3D objects in three.JS
are made up of two parts.
A geometry that defines
the shape of the object,
and the material that
defines the surface quality,
the appearance of the object.
The combination of these two things
makes up a mesh in three.JS
which forms the 3D object.
Three.JS allows us to
create some simple shapes
like a cube, or a sphere,
in an easy manner.
To be able to create a cube,
we could use the "box geometry" function
by providing the dimensions, the width,
the height, and the depth.
So I'm going to create a
variable called "geometry,"
and I call the three.JS
"box geometry" function
with the values
the width, the height, and the depth,
and now I need to create a
material for this geometry
as well.
There are various kinds of materials
that we could use on geometries.
Materials determine how an object reacts
to the scene lighting.
We can use a material to
make an object reflective,
rough, transparent, et cetera.
The default material that
three.JS objects are created with
is the mesh basic material.
Mesh basic material is not
affected by the scene lighting
at all.
This means that our geometry's
going to be visible,
even when there's no
lighting in the scene.
So let's create a mesh basic material
by calling the "three.JS mesh
basic material" function,
and to mesh basic material function,
we can pass a color parameter
that will define the color of the object.
You can define the color using hex values.
I'm going to be using the
hex value for the green color
for this material.
With the geometry and material at hand,
we can combine these two to create a mesh,
which is going to form the 3D object.
So to be able to create a mesh,
I'm going to be calling the new
"Three mesh" function,
and then,
to this function I will
be passing the geometry,
and the material
as arguments.
And now, now that I
created the mesh object,
I can add this object to the scene
by using the "scene
.add" method.
Having done all this,
I should start seeing things
on the screen actually,
but before I look at my three.JS scene,
I would like to actually
contain all these commands
inside a function so that I can easily
call them later on.
So I will be creating a
function called "get box"
that is going to encapsulate
this functionality.
Going to copy this section,
and create a function called "get box,"
that's going to get the width, height,
and the depth as arguments.
And I'm going to paste
all that code inside here.
And I'm going to return
the mesh object from this.
And here,
I can delete this functionality
and just call my function.
Perfect!
Now, I should be using this variable name,
which is the box,
to add to the scene,
and now this box is being added to scene,
which means that if I'm
to go back to Chrome,
I should expect to see a box in there.
So let's switch to Chrome
to see what we have.
Hmmm, it seems like we are still
getting a black screen here.
To be able to illustrate what's going on,
I'm going to be using the three.JS editor.
Three.JS editor is a web-based 3D editor
that is built on top
of three.JS technology.
It allows us to control the
scene in a visual manner.
You can find it at the
address "threejs.org/editor."
The reason why don't we see
anything right now in our scene
is, whenever we create something in 3D,
we are creating it at the
0, 0, 0 coordinate space.
So let's create a box
using the three.JS editor
to see where it is being created at.
As you can see, it is being created at,
at the center of the scene.
The reason why we don't see
anything right now is that,
whenever you add an object
to the scene in three.JS,
the object gets placed at
the center of the scene,
at the coordinates of 0, 0, 0,
for x, y, and z.
This is what the coordinate space
for the three.JS looks like.
With the y axis pointing upwards,
and the other two axes, the x,
and the z axis,
pointing in other directions.
So, what's happening right now is that,
our box is at the
coordinate space of 0, 0, 0,
and now we are creating a camera
at this coordinate space as well.
They are superimposed at
the same coordinate space,
meaning that the camera
is unable to see the box.
So to be able to make the camera
to be able to see the box,
we can either move the
box in the z direction,
in the negative z direction,
or, we can move the camera
in the positive z direction,
so that they can see each other.
In our case, we will be moving the camera
5 units on the z axis.
This is achieved by setting
the position property
on the camera.
Let's do that.
So here, back at the scene,
if we are to change the position
z attribute of the camera
to 5,
and now if I'm to go back to the scene,
I should be able to start seeing things.
Objects in three.JS
have 3 attributes called
position, rotation, and scale,
that you can use to transform them.
All these attributes
have 3 more attributes
for you choose which axis
you would like to perform
the transformation on.
In this case, we moved the camera
using its position
attribute on the z axis.
After doing this change, as you can see,
we can see the box in our scene finally.
But the object doesn't look very 3D,
it looks very flat right now,
as if it is a 2D image.
So let's move the camera
1 unit on the x axis,
and 2 units on the y axis.
Going back into my main js file,
I will be doing those changes.
Here, we are already moving the camera
on the z axis by 5 units.
I will also move it on the x axis
by 1 unit,
and I will also move it on the y axis
by 2 units.
Now, if I am to check back to Chrome,
we are starting to see that
we are getting some more
dimensionality from the object.
We can actually tell that this
is not a simple rectangle,
but it is a box.
But the camera is not
pointing to the box anymore.
The box is not centered in the frame.
To be able to fix that,
we should be adjusting a
property called "look at"
on the camera.
"Look at" is a method on the camera
that determines which point
the camera is looking at.
The points in the 3D space
are represented by vectors.
So we can pass a new vector object
to this "look at" method
to be able to have our camera look at the
0, 0, 0 coordinates.
So I'm going to be calling
the "look at" method
on the camera,
and I'm going to be passing a new three.JS
vector tree object,
which represents a point in 3D space
for the camera to be looking at.
So if I am to save the scene right now,
and look at Chrome again,
we can see that the
object is now being centered
in the middle of the screen.