- [Instructor] Looking
back at the main js file,
I'm noticing that the
"get box" function takes
width, height, and depth as arguments,
but is not really making use of them.
So I'm going to change this,
and get rid of the hard coded values here,
and make use of the width,
height, and depth values.
So that when we are calling this function,
we can actually parameterize
the creation of the box.
And now, I'm going to add a
plane to the screen as well.
For this purpose,
I can use the plane geometry object.
Plane geometry requires
us to pass the width,
and the height parameter
to set the size of the plane
that we would like to create.
So to be able to do so,
I will create a dedicated function
for plane as well.
Just like how I created
the "get box" function,
I'm going to create a
"get plane" function,
using most of the parameters,
or commands that I used here,
and name it, instead of "get box,"
"get plane,"
and I'm going to be calling
the "plane geometry" function.
Plane geometry have a different signature
than box geometry.
It works with width,
and depth values,
so I'm going to be
passing a single argument
to the get plane,
and I will be using it,
to (speaks softly) here,
to be able to set the width
and the depth
of the plane geometry.
And now this is pretty much it,
but one more thing that we need to do
when creating a plane function,
or plane object in three.JS,
is we need to define a size
parameter here as well.
Because in 3D, 2-dimensional flat objects
don't have both of their
sides displayed by default.
So to be able to see the
other side of the objects,
we need to pass a attribute called
"three.doublesides"
for the 2D objects as well.
Having done this, we should
be able to get a ground plane
on our scene.
So here,
I'm going to be calling that function,
by providing the value 4 to it.
And I will be adding the
plane to the scene as well.
Every time we are creating
an object in three.JS,
we need to add it to the scene
to be able to see it.
And now, if I am to save the scene,
and look at the results,
I should be able to see a plane.
Perfect!
Now we are seeing the plane as well,
but plane is using the
same color as the box,
so we can't really tell the difference.
So I'm going to go back and
change the color of the plane
to red.
Here instead of using the hex
value for the green color,
I will be using the hex
value for the red color.
And now we have a red
plane, on the screen.
But I would like to have this
plane horizontal to the ground
so that I will rotate it 90
degrees around this x axis.
Now, if I am to go back to Chrome,
and look at the scene,
I can notice that the rotation happens,
but it doesn't seem to be 90 degrees,
it seems to be less than that.
Or it could be more than that as well,
but it doesn't seem to be the
90 degrees that I provided.
The reason for that is,
three.JS is using radiants,
instead of angles, to do rotation.
90 degrees in radiants
would be the pi value
divided by 2.
We can get the pi value
using the Javascript
math object.
So I'm going to go back to my code,
and instead of using 90 degrees here,
I'm going to be calling "math PI"
to be able to get the pi value
and divide it by 2.
This should provide me
with the 90 degrees that I'm looking for.
Perfect!
Now you would notice,
some portion of the cube seems to be under
the plane geometry.
The reason for this is that
the box geometry gets placed in the scene
from a center,
meaning that half of the box
will be under the ground plane.
Let's move the box half
of its current size,
which is 1, so that box
will remain on the plane.
So I'm going to go back, and here,
I'm going to position the box
on the y axis
by 0.5,
and doing so should move the box on top
of the ground plane.
This is good, and works
for our current purposes,
but if the height of
the box were to change,
then you would need to
update this code as well.
This is only working for
a box of the height 1.
A better way of going about this
would be to fetch the height of the box,
the current height of the box,
and use that value for
the positioning purposes.
We can get the height value of the box
from its geometry attribute.
So instead of hard coding the value here,
what I can do is, I can call
the "box geometry" attribute,
look at its parameters,
and get the height value from here,
and divide it by 2.
Doing so, we should be
able to position the box
from its bottom, instead
of it's being positioned
from its center.
So let's look at the scene,
and we will see that the
box is being positioned
from its bottom points right now.
No matter what the height of the box is,
it will always remain on the grids.
Having done all this,
we built a very simple scene in three.JS.
Granted our scene doesn't
look like much at the moment,
but we will be improving
the look of the things
as we learn more about
the three.JS features
in the next chapter.